Ah , the Heckler Koch G-36 .
Quite deadly in the right hands .
Ah , Agent One .
I have been so looking forward to this moment .
Well , in that case , I 'll try not to disappoint .
You overestimate your power over women , Mr English .
I 'd say that would be virtually impossible .
Sir ? Sir ?
- Sir ! Have you got them ?
- Hmm ? - The mission documents . Agent One 's flying tonight .
Yes , the mission documents . They 're here somewhere . Ah , here we are .
Agent One .
Gentlemen .
I 'm here for my documents .
Bough , Agent One 's documents , please .
- Thank you .
Your mission documents , Agent One .
Including the codes for the submarine hatch , which I 've checked myself .
Thank you .
So , is it just France tonight , or will you be slipping over the Pyrenees as well ?
If I told you that , I 'm afraid I 'd have to kill you .
Oh .
Oh , yes , yes . Well , I expect you would .
Cheerio , Agent One .
Bonne chance . Arrivederci .
Such class . Such distinction .
To : Ml7 All Depts . Urgent Agent One killed in action in Biarritz .
Submarine hatch failed to open .
The greatest secret agent England 's ever had snuffed out in an instant .
Terrible .
Do you know what makes us envied the world over , Bough ?
- That there 's always another agent waiting to step in . - Absolutely , sir .
And every last one of them is gathered around that grave .
It is our honour and privilege to guard them while they grieve .
Their lives are in our hands , Bough .
Everything in order , English ?
I think you 'll find it 's rather more than just in order , sir .
You 're now entering the most secure location in the whole of England .
Pegasus , we face a national crisis .
Agent One was clearly onto something , and we have to find out what .
I need another agent on this . Who else is there ?
No one , Prime Minister . They all died in the explosion .
All of them ?
Well , luckily there is one who survived .
Who ?
# # One eye on the shadows # #
# # Protecting his fellows # #
- # # From sunup till the moon on his back # #
- # # Sendin ' villains to Hades A hit with the ladies # # - Johnny English .
# # A stallion in the sack # #
- # # You can 't get your life back when right follows left , Jack # #
# # The more you see the less you know # #
# # When others would leak it His service is secret # #
# # Plays God when it 's your time to go # #
# # Hey , fellas Don 't be jealous # #
# # When they made him they broke the mould # #
# # So charismatic with an automatic # #
# # Never prematurely shooting his load # #
Hah !
# # Queen and country safe and sound # #
# # With villains six feet underground # #
# # And no one knows ' cause no one 's found any trace # #
# # Of a man for all seasons # #
# # Loves ' em and leaves ' em alone # #
# # So alone # #
# # And you and I wouldn 't have a clue who 's doin ' what , why , when and who # #
# # Up a creek with no canoe Watch out # #
# # For the man for all seasons # #
# # Loves ' em and leaves ' em alone # #
# # So alone # #
- # # But safe at home # # - # # But safe at home # #
- # # Oh , yeah , yeah # # - # # But safe at home # #
# # But safe at home But safe at home # #
# # Then you and I wouldn 't have a clue who 's doin ' what , why , when and who # #
# # Up a creek with no canoe Watch out # #
# # For the man for all seasons # #
# # Loves ' em and leaves ' em alone , so alone # #
# # But safe at home # #
Right .
Johnny English . I 'm here to see Pegasus .
Still , no sense rushing things .
There are some items you need to sign before your briefing .
This is your new retinal I.D. Card ,
and this is your level nine security clearance .
Sign and date , please .
Ah .
Oh , reminds me of the old service issue ballpoint .
I remember every agent would carry a pen that looked just like this .
Completely innocent to the untrained eye , but click it twice ...
Ah , English , there you are .
Have you seen my secretary ?
Um ... she went out .
Um ... shall we ?
Now , Agent One believed that there was a plot to steal the Crown Jewels .
They 've recently been through a multimillion-pound restoration ,
largely paid for by a corporate sponsor .
They 're due to be unveiled tonight at the Tower of London .
The queen is insisting that the ceremony goes ahead , so what we want you to ...
Hah ! Who ... Who ...
Who is the sponsor , sir ?
Pascal Sauvage .
What , that flouncy Frenchman who owns a couple of prisons ?
Sauvage 's £ 7 billion empire , English ,
operates over 400 prisons in 60 countries .
- He 's built 25 of them here . - Right , sir .
The man 's related to the royal family , for goodness ' sake .
As far as the prime minister 's concerned , he 's one of the greatest friends England 's got .
Now , English , I want you at the Tower tonight , monitoring this unveiling .
Any chink in security , any weakness ,
however slight , must be plugged immediately .
Do we understand each other ?
- Perfectly , sir . - Good .
- Oh , yes . - And , uh , English ...
we can 't afford any mistakes ... not tonight .
The word " mistake , " sir , is not one that appears in my dictionary .
THE TOWER OF LONDON
Fantastic car , sir !
Mr English , Colonel Sir Anthony Chevenix , head of Royal Security .
Ah , Colonel , good evening .
- Snipers posted on the roof as per my request ? - Thirteen of them .
- Windows ? - Refitted with bullet - and shatter-proof glass .
I shall now mingle inconspicuously with the guests .
- Let me know when Her Majesty arrives . - Very good .
Shall I mingle with you , sir ?
Oh , yes , Bough . Once you 've checked the roof .
Help ! Help !
Well , hello .
Hello yourself .
Johnny English .
Lorna Campbell .
A Bloody Mary , please , not too spicy .
So , are you here in some professional capacity ?
I worked on the restoration of the jewels .
- Intriguing . - And yourself ?
If I told you that , I 'm afraid I 'd have to kill you .
I 'd like to see you try .
Monsieur Sauvage , on behalf of Her Majesty ,
may I welcome you to the Tower .
Merci , monsieur .
So , are you here alone , Mr English ?
That 's how I choose to live my life , Miss Campbell .
Women want safety , security . I can offer them nothing but danger .
Some women find danger very attractive .
Women like you , Miss Campbell ?
Women like me expect men like you ...
to find that out for yourself .
Hmm .
Madame .
Oh , it 's for me , actually . Could your rustle up some of those cheesy niblets ?
Now , where were we ?
You obviously haven 't met our host , Monsieur Sauvage .
No , thank God .
You know , I think I 'd rather have my bottom impaled on a giant cactus ...
than exchange pleasantries with that jumped-up Frenchman .
As far as I 'm concerned , the only thing the French should host is an invasion .
Sorry , can I help ?
Pascal Sauvage , jumped-up Frenchman .
Lorna Campbell . I 've been so looking forward to meeting you .
- Enchanté .
But of course ! You 're Johnny English . I 've heard all about you .
And between you and me , I 'm not so keen on the French myself .
But please don 't tell them that .
Let me go and search for your nibbly cheese bits .
- No , no , no . L ... - I insist . The French are , after all , fantastic waiters .
- The best in the world . - Well ... But-But ...
- Wait here , and I will wait on you . - No , really . There 's no ...
No . Please , please , please !
Hmm . Les Français .
Ils sont very ... n 'est-ce pas ?
Ladies and gentlemen , mesdames est messieurs ,
bienvenus , welcome tonight to this wonderful occasion .
As we stand here in the Tower of London ,
the most famous prison in the world ,
where these wonderful jewels will rest safely ...
under lock and key ,
I want to thank you ...
for giving me this wonderful experience ...
to contribute to the restoration of these jewels .
It was , as we say in France , le top , le best of .
- And what a beautiful ...
It 's Colonel Chevenix ! He 's got a nasty wound , sir . Who hit him ?
The assailant . He ran in here .
Bough , you guard the door .
Aha !
For God 's sake , Bough , don 't come in . The man 's a maniac !
- You don 't frighten me !
- - Missed !
- - I 've managed to subdue the assailant .
The panic 's over . Everything 's under control .
-
Thank you . And now , ladies and gentlemen ,
we should compose ourselves for the arrival of Her Majesty ...
and return to the site of our great nation 's ...
magnificently restored Crown Jewels .
I know . I feel it too .
The very symbols of our island nation ,
so close we could almost reach out and ...
- Pray silence for Her Majesty the Queen .
Oh , where are the jewels ?
It 's an unmitigated disaster , English .
I couldn 't agree more , sir .
Well , we need to get these jewels back , English , and fast .
Tell me about this assailant . When they searched the room , there was no sign of him .
Well , the man was clearly a professional .
He must have escaped while the queen was being sedated .
But he 's the only lead we 've got . We have to find him .
Come in . This is ... This is Roger from Data Support .
Please sit down . He 'll produce a likeness based on your description .
So tell us , what did this man look like ?
Um ... well ...
he was ... big .
- Hair colour ? - Um ... orange .
- Orange ? - Mmm . And curly .
Well , frizzy , actually . Frizzy sort of thing .
- Frizzy . - An eyepatch .
Broken nose . Very few teeth .
Two , I would say , at the most .
And a scar on his cheek ...
in the shape ... of a banana .
- Which cheek ? - Both cheeks .
They sort of met in the middle .
Are you sure about this , English ?
Oh , yes , that 's him . An uncanny resemblance .
Why , it 's just as if he 's in the room with us .
Wow ! Look at this , sir . Got all the bells and whistles .
Never mind about the gadgets . Just focus on the case .
Oh , uh ...
Good morning , gentlemen . Thank you very much for waiting .
Now , the question that faces us this morning is a simple one .
Namely , how did the thieves gain access to this highly secure environment ...
and then escape with the jewels afterwards ?
A simple question , but one which I believe has a complex answer .
- Actually , sir ... - Uh , please , Bough . My mind is at work .
Now , what you must grasp , gentlemen , is that the master criminal ...
sees not a room but a series of opportunities .
Should I go in through the window ?
Possibly .
- Should I drop down from the ceiling ? - Actually , sir ...
There 's one thing I think we can be fairly confident about ,
that is that they didn 't come up through the floor ...
I 've got you , sir .
That 's all right . Just come my way , Bough .
- That 'll bring me right over the hole , sir . - There 's no need to panic .
Can you see the bottom yet , Bough ?
Not yet , sir . The shaft appears to be narrowing .
I 'm just a little bit worried I might get stuck .
Trust me , Bough . You won 't get stuck if you just keep moving .
Yes , sir .
I 'm okay , sir .
Are you at the bottom now , Bough ?
No , I am in fact stuck now , sir .
Oh , for God 's sake , Bough . Stay there ! I 'm coming down .
Uh , I 'm not especially sure that 's a good idea , sir .
Don 't worry .
Be careful , sir !
Gently does it .
- Sir ?
- Are you all right , sir ? - Yes . I landed on something quite soft .
- That was me , sir . - Oh , good .
What now ?
There 's no way back up there , that 's for sure .
But this must lead somewhere .
I 'm slightly uncomfortable in the dark , sir .
There 's nothing to worry about , Bough .
- It may be pitch black , but we can still see . - Can we , sir ? How ?
The Bedouin monks of the Al Maghreb mountains ...
developed a system of sonic chanting .
- I see , sir . - The sound of their chanting ...
would bounce back off any obstacles ,
and using their highly tuned ears ...
they could paint a mental picture of the path ahead .
- Brilliant , sir . - However , you must always sing in E-flat .
# E-flat , E-flat , E-flat #
# Thank you for the music The songs I 'm singing #
- Is it working , sir ? - Extremely well , thank you , Bough .
# Thanks for all the joy that ... #
- - Ow !
You all right , sir ? I think I can see something , sir .
Oh , yeah . Come on .
Here is the long one .
It is a long one .
Careful .
- I knew it . - Shall we call for backup , sir ?
What ? And watch some fat-bottomed bobby make our arrest for us ?
I don 't think so .
Good morning , gentlemen . Ml7 at your service .
Observe , Bough , the dull incompetence of the criminal mind .
It can never hope to match our level of technical expertise .
- You 've got it . - What do we do now , sir ?
Watch and learn , Bough .
- They 're too far ahead of us . - Have faith , Bough . They 're heading south .
- There they are , sir ! - Just as I thought .
- Hang on tight , Bough .
- We 're never gonna catch them in this .
- Take the wheel , Bough . I 'm getting in the Aston . - Sir ?
Change places , Bough . I 'm getting out the other side .
Sir ?
Set , Bough . Take me up .
Swing me out , Bough !
- Whoa . - Down .
- Up ! Up !
Sorry !
Bough , pull out !
Ow ! Ow !
Those idiots are right behind us . Faster !
Uh-huh .
Drop me here , Bough !
Ow ! Oh .
No ! No ! No !
Oh , no , no , no , no , no , no .
They 're turning into the Brompton Cemetery .
Get here as soon as you can . I 'm going in .
In a wheelchair . But Geoffrey overcame these terrible disabilities ...
with that simple resilience and sunny optimism ...
that so warmed all of us who knew him ,
spending the rest of his life in the service ...
of the poor and disabled of this parish .
It 's very good . Really very good .
No , no , please go on . I 'm sorry to interrupt .
- It 's very entertaining . - Who 's that ?
That priest act of yours should keep the other prisoners entertained for hours .
Oh , I 'm so sorry . Where are my manners ? Johnny English ,
British Secret Service , and you are all under arrest .
I must say you 've done this whole thing very well .
The attention to detail is excellent .
You , the grieving granny , you 're very convincing .
Oh , look . Real tears . Do you get paid extra for that ?
Ahh , what we 're all here for .
I know ! Why don 't we take a look inside ?
- - Oh , you 've nailed it down !
Why would you do that ?
I know you 're gonna come back in two weeks and dig it up again .
Now , what are you playing in this little vignette of deceit and villainy ?
I 'm the hearse driver .
- You 're the hearse driver ? - Yes , sir .
Ah ! Aha !
There you are ... Gunther .
Uh , I do hope he hasn 't made a nuisance of himself .
I 'm Doctor , um ...
Bough , of the Lunatic Response Unit .
I 'm afraid Gunther here wasn 't supposed to be released until 2028 .
Isn 't that right , Gunther ?
Yes , yes , there 's been the most monumental cock-up .
Um , if you 'll excuse me , with the deepest respect ,
utmost sympathy .
Uh , he hasn 't urinated on anyone , has he ?
- No . - No , no .
That 's a blessing . Are you gonna give me the gun , Gunther ?
There . That wasn 't too difficult , was it ?
- Are you going to come home now ?
Oh ... in the van ! Yes , we are going in the van .
Yes , yes . Vroom , vroom .
- Vroom , vroom . Vroom , vroom . - Yes . Yeah .
- Yes . He 's waving good-bye . Good-bye , everyone .
- Good-bye . - Good-bye , Gunther .
Mind the nice dead people . There we go .
Oh , we 'll just go to the path here . There . Big step .
It 's a graveyard . It 's where they bring people ...
Yes , all right . You can stop now .
- For appearances , I 'll just hold your arm . - Just keep walking .
In fact , run , run , run !
I can 't believe I 've done this .
I mean , I really cannot believe I 've done this !
You see , 200 years ago ,
my family should have inherited the throne of England ,
but they were cast aside .
Well , in a few very short days ,
it will be back where it belongs .
With me .
Shall I try it on ? Yes ? No ? Maybe ?
To make you king , we need the archbishop of Canterbury to do that .
The archbishop of Canterbury ...
is being taken care of even as we speak . TARGET ACQUIRED
TARGET LOCKED
There 's only one thing , sir . What are we going to do about English ?
If I were you , I wouldn 't worry too much about English .
He is no threat to us . I had his flat bugged .
Clearly , the aptly named English is a fool .
He might be a fool , but he 's a fool who keeps showing up .
Well , the next time he shows up ,
eliminate him .
Thank you .
Dieter Klein and Klaus Vendetta , sir .
Released from prison six months ago . 327 convictions between them .
Armed robbery , grievous bodily harm ...
and combined parking fines of more than 400 ...
Uh , yes , all right . Thank you , Bough . I think we get the picture .
The point is , sir , that Vendetta and Klein ...
are both in the employ of Monsieur Sauvage .
- Pascal Sauvage ? - Precisely , sir .
But you 're not suggesting Sauvage is involved ?
I think he 's more than just involved , sir .
I 'm convinced he 's up to his French neck in it .
Don 't be absurd . Sauvage employs thousands of people .
Just because two of them are villains doesn 't mean that he is .
I want him discounted from this investigation immediately .
Yes , sir .
All right . Tonight I shall be at Sauvage 's reception for the new French ambassador .
Any developments , you can reach me there .
Apart from that , I don 't want you within a hundred miles of the man .
Absolutely , sir .
Requisition order : Ml7 quartermasters for immediate supply ;
one military transport plane , fully fueled , with permission for nighttime city over flight ;
two night camouflage parachutes , plus reserves , plus neoprene bodysuits , twice , in black .
I 've never liked the navy blue .
And a 40-inch chest for me 'cause I need the sleeve length .
- Morning , Felch . - Morning .
Oh , and two Special Forces signet rings ,
primed and colour-coded .
- What 's all this for ? - For tonight 's operation .
We 're going to break into Sauvage 's headquarters .
- But Pegasus said ... - Let me worry about Pegasus .
I know that Sauvage is behind all this , and tonight we 're going to get the evidence .
- Is something wrong , sir ? - Did that sound like Felch to you ?
Bough ...
You , upstairs .
Ow .
Can you see him , Bough ?
He 's on the upper level , sir .
Got him .
And like a coiled viper ... he strikes .
So what you 're saying , sir , is there must have been two of them ?
Oh , at least , Bough . Possibly four .
I wonder why I didn 't see them .
You mustn 't dwell on your mistakes .
- You must learn from them , then move on . - Yes , sir .
- So where were you , sir ? - Just drop it , Bough !
- Aah ! What is it , sir ? - That bike .
You get things sorted out for tonight .
Well , well , we meet again .
Mr English . What a pleasant surprise .
I wondered when you might show up again .
On the contrary , Miss Campbell . It is not I who keeps showing up . It 's you .
Do you like sushi ?
Hmm ?
Oh , sushi ! I practically live off the stuff .
You might say the mysteries of the Orient are no mystery to me .
- Sake ? - Ah . Sake .
Cheers .
May all your daughters be born with three bottoms .
Now then , perhaps you can explain how it is ...
that I run into you at two crime scenes ...
and then can 't find any record of you on a single government computer .
Shouldn 't you ask the government that ?
I am the government and I 'm asking you .
Let me .
Mmm . You 're brave .
They say that sea urchin 's the ultimate acquired taste .
Hmm . It 's a personal favourite of mine .
I think people are put off by how it feeds through its bottom .
Would you excuse me for a moment ?
Excuse me . Sorry . I 'm from Ml7 . Sorry . I 'm a secret agent .
- Everything set , Bough ? - Just about , sir .
Actually , sir , do you mind if I run through the plan one more time ?
- No , no . - These are the two buildings here .
This one is our target , Sauvage 's headquarters , next to City Hospital .
I jump first and land on the south side of the roof ,
abseil down 14 floors and cut through this window here .
I then land on the east side and abseil down 12 floors .
Where you wait for my signal that I 've disabled the alarm system .
- Yes . - You them break into this window here ,
work your way along the secure corridor and penetrate Sauvage 's office .
- Yes , yes . - Is that okay , sir ?
It 's been okay ever since I thought up the idea , Bough .
Oh , I nearly forgot , sir . Your laser beacon .
- My what ? - Your laser beacon !
It 'll guide you onto Sauvage 's building .
Your dependence on hardware really does amuse me , Bough .
I 've been dropped into the Kalahari Desert ...
carrying nothing more than a toothbrush and a packet of sherbet lemons ,
and I still found my way to Bulawayo before Ramadan .
So thank you , Bough , but no thank you .
- Bough , go !
Geronimo !
- Fandango !
Ugh ! Ai-yi-yi .
Right .
- Alarm 's disabled , sir .
Roger that , Bough .
This is worse than I thought , Bough .
Sauvage has got some kind of laboratory set up here .
God knows what kind of sick operation he 's running .
My God , what have they done to you ?
They 've taken some of my blood .
- Bastards ! - It 's only for tests .
Of course it is . Come on , my friend .
Let 's get you out of here before they take anything else .
Ah ! Good evening , Dr Frankenstein .
This way , please .
Come on . I haven 't got all night .
And you , you angels of death .
About turn . Come on , let 's go .
Come On , come On . Keep moving .
Come on . Over there . I know what you 're doing here . And you .
Come on . Quicker . Quicker . Over there .
Now then ,
perhaps you could direct me to your evil paymaster .
- What are you talking about ? - You know exactly what I 'm talking about .
Where is the office of Pascal Sauvage ?
Are you coming over here in a minute , sir ?
I 'm from Ml7 .
This has been a test of your emergency response systems ,
and I have to say you 've all done extremely well .
Right . Well , I 'll leave you to it .
And , uh , get well soon .
Oh , God !
Sir . Sir .
Did you just land on the wrong building ?
I did a precautionary sweep of the immediate environment .
Right .
- And everything was fine . - Good .
Okay , let 's go .
I will be downstairs at the reception ...
- That 's far enough . - Well , good evening .
- Perhaps you 'd like this as well . - What is it ?
- Let me show you . - Aah !
Well executed , Bough , but completely redundant .
- How do you mean , sir ? - Super-strength muscle relaxant .
When he wakes up , he 'll be as floppy as a damp old sock .
What 's this ?
That 's the face of the archbishop of Canterbury .
What are they doing ?
What 's this got to do with the Crown Jewels ?
Bough .
English .
A people whose empire once covered ...
one quarter of the surface of the earth .
Alas , no longer .
My friends ask me , " Pascal , how can you be so interested ...
in such a backward , grotty little country ? "
My answer is simple : The queen .
The queen has more power in her tiny white gloves ...
than any other head of state in the entire world .
She can declare war or make peace ,
and most intriguingly ...
she can seize any piece of land which takes her fancy .
Of course , the queen never uses ...
the enormous power afforded to her .
But imagine someone who would use that power .
Imagine , say , me .
But how could he do that , sir ? How could he make himself king ?
The archbishop .
- -
Ow .
Hands up . There 's a good fellow .
Heavily armed for a late night at the office .
You fool , English . You 'll never get out of the building alive .
I 'd save your breath for my questioning .
I 'm not telling you anything .
Incorrect .
Sodium pentothal .
- I won 't lie to you . It 's a truth serum .
Now then , why does Sauvage want to have himself crowned ?
You have no idea what 's going on here , do you ?
It would be funny if it wasn 't so " pablibblit . "
What ?
- He 's talking gibberish , sir . - I can hear that .
- He 's collapsed onto me , sir . - I can see that .
- You don 't think you could 've got the syringes mixed up ? - What ?
Given the guard outside truth serum and given Klein the muscle relaxant ?
Aah !
Don 't be ridiculous , Bough . I think I know my right from my left .
- Sir ? - Oh , bugger it .
Bough , take " flodd . "
- Take what , sir ? - " Flodd . " " Schlage . "
- I 'm not quite getting that second word , sir . - " Schlaaaagh ! "
- Write it down , sir . - " Schlaaaagh ! "
Yes !
" C. " C-A ... Uh ...
Car ! Take the car ! We came by plane .
Bugger off !
- Hold it right there .
- What 's wrong with them ? - I 'm not telling you .
Wrong answer .
What is it with you two ?
Huh ?
Let 's get outta here .
Sorry , but who are you , exactly ?
Special Agent Campbell . I 'm attached to Interpol in Paris .
We 've been watching Sauvage for months .
Why ?
Because every major convict released from a Sauvage prison in six months ...
has been employed by one of his companies .
We believe he 's recruiting them for a major criminal conspiracy .
- We just don 't know what yet . -
- What did he say ? - Pegasus !
We have to report to Pegasus !
Oh , no , sir . No , no , no .
- How do we get out of here ? - Hey , you two !
What you did to me really hurt .
Yeah . Sorry about that . How do we get out of here without being seen ?
Okay .
Left by the fountain , right by the fire exit , to the elevator at the end .
- Thank you . - Oh , my God .
Nice job , Bough .
- Left , sir . Left !
Sir , you can 't go to Sauvage 's reception in this state .
The effect of the drug has practically worn off .
I 'm " fline " ...
" schline " ... uh , " gline " ...
- Monsieur . - Ah . Thank you .
- Would you like another ? - Please .
Thank you .
What in God 's name ...
Ah , Foreign " Sebretarary . "
Um ...
Aah !
- Shall we dance ?
Excuse me , sir . I 'm very sorry to interrupt ...
Pascal , how nice to see you again .
- Enjoying the party ? - Oh , splendid affair .
I was until I was informed that your man English ...
and his curious boyfriend here have spent the evening ...
breaking into my office and assaulting my staff .
- Is this true , Bough ? - Well , we ... we ...
What do you think you 're up to ?
- Sir , if I could just offer ... - Go home , Bough !
Now !
I gave you direct orders not to meddle with Sauvage .
What do you do ? Break into his office and assault two of his staff .
Then you march in here , loaded with God knows what , and insult the foreign secretary .
I haven 't encountered such behaviour in Whitehall in 30 years .
- But ... - There are no " buts , " English .
You 're off the case . Your security clearance is hereby cancelled .
After a three-month leave of absence , you will return at your old grade .
And I hope never to hear your name again .
English has seen too much .
We go to plan " B. "
Get rid of the fake archbishop ...
and green-light the visit to Her Majesty .
Then this pathetic country can humiliate itself ...
by crowning me officially .
THE QUEEN 'S RESIDENCE AT SANDRINGHAM
That 's a letter of abdication ...
renouncing your claims to the throne ...
and the claims of your entire family .
Sign it .
Never .
- Yes ?
Prime Minister , sorry to call so late , but I 'm afraid the queen is abdicating .
What ?
Abdicated ? But that 's not possible .
I only wish that were true .
- Let me talk to her . Maybe she just ... - Pascal , she 's gone .
My people have spent the last 10 hours ...
trying to track down the rightful heir to the throne ...
and they 've come up with a name , which they 've double-checked .
Who is it ?
- It 's you . - No !
In the wake of the return of the Crown Jewels ...
to a police station in North London ,
Pascal Sauvage has requested that his coronation ...
take place this Thursday .
In the House , the prime minister said he was looking forward to the ceremony ...
and he believed that Monsieur Sauvage will make a fine king ...
and will bring all that is best about modern Europe to our ancient institutions .
Get your car keys . We 've got work to do .
- Miss Campbell . - Sauvage is heading back to France .
He 's invited 13 of the richest criminal masterminds in the world to meet him there .
I 'm sorry , Miss Campbell . I 'm off the case .
It 's been reassigned .
I know . Reassigned to me .
- I want you with me . - Just leave me alone .
Are you gonna sit here in this grotty flat feeling sorry for yourself ?
Or are you gonna get out there and save your country ?
I 'm gonna sit in the flat .
- Johnny , this is ridiculous . - I 'm a spent force .
Spent , my ass .
Ow .
Will ... you ... please ... stop ?
I 'll just be a minute .
NORTHERN FRANCE
It 'll be nightfall in an hour . Then we can strike out for the chateau .
The fact is , the moment Sauvage gets that crown on his head ,
he 'll be able to do whatever he likes with the country that I love ,
and that is why you and I have got to stop him .
- Relishing the thought ? - Something like that .
I suppose you 've made love to lots of women , haven 't you , Johnny ?
Uh ... Uh , well , you know ,
one does one 's best .
It 's just ...
Well , it 's been three years since my fiancé left me ,
and since then I haven 't made love to anyone .
But then I met you ...
and I felt this ... hunger ...
deep down inside .
I wanted to say things to you , I wanted to do things to you ...
that I haven 't wanted to do in a very , very , very long time .
What , uh ...
What sort of things are we talking about ?
Things like punching you in the face ,
kicking you in the backside for being such a pompous , know-nothing asshole .
But then I started to see beyond the idiot that everybody else saw .
I started to see the man on the inside ...
who was determined to do his duty , no matter what or who lay in his way .
And I began to feel other things for him ,
to want to do other things for him .
Things ...
involving plastic toys and soft cheese ?
- What ? - What ? What ?
You 're toying with me . You 're telling me to stop in the gentlest way you know how .
No . N-N-No ...
You 're such a special person ...
not to take advantage of me while I 'm vulnerable .
- N-No ... Well ... - So thank you ...
for being such a gentleman .
Not at all .
I know what you 're thinking , Miss Campbell .
If we don 't pull this off , God knows what might happen to England .
Actually , I was thinking there must be a better way in than that pipe .
Well , there isn 't .
I 've analysed it from every angle , and this is the best option .
I 'll go in first , and if it 's a clear way through , I 'll call down .
Johnny .
- Be careful . - I 'm always careful .
Ohh .
- Gentlemen .
In a few hours time ...
I will become the next king of England .
Oh , no .
Hyah ...
- How did you get here ? - Up the ladder .
Pull yourself together . It 's only a bit of poo .
Oh ! Oh , it 's cold ! It 's cold !
What is the one commodity ...
the world never seems to run out of ?
Criminals , gentlemen .
- - Lawbreakers .
Every nation in the world struggles ...
with the issue of overcrowded prisons .
So , what do we do with all these villains ?
Find the solution to that problem ...
and the governments of the world would pay you through their nose .
Fortunately , I have found a solution .
We empty every prison on the entire planet ,
we take the resulting tidal wave of human scum ...
and we put it here .
The moment I am crowned king ,
I will turn England into the largest prison ...
in the history of the world .
210,000 square miles ...
of prime real estate ...
conveniently separated from true civilization ...
by 20 miles of ocean ...
- and soon to be available ... - Come on .
For the entire world to dump its human waste in .
According to current projections ,
we will not run out of prison space for the next 500 years .
So , tonight one , and only one , of you ...
will leave here owning 49 percent ...
of this venture .
So that 's his little game . We must get hold of that DVD .
But how , Johnny ? There 's only two of us .
You 're young , Miss Campbell , and inexperienced .
What you seem to have forgotten is that ...
Nobody knows we are here .
At our disposal we have the vital element of surprise .
Now , my plan is simple but effective .
I shall drop from the gallery at this end of the room and take Sauvage prisoner .
You will then enter from the far door , cutting off any means of escape .
Then , using Sauvage as a hostage , we 'll get the hell out of here . Clear ?
Get ' em up , you French ponce .
But , Mr English , I 'm gobsmacked !
What an unexpected surprise .
Surprises are very much my speciality , Sauvage .
I think we 've seen enough of this .
I know exactly what you 're planning , and I 'm here to put a stop to it .
My bottom will be king of England before you are .
Wrong again .
Perhaps you 'd care to look behind you .
Oh , please .
Lorna !
I 'm sorry , Johnny .
Well , I 'm afraid that we 'll have to ...
conclude the floor show for tonight .
Not so fast , Sauvage .
You may have taken me , but you 'll never take England .
Not as long as I have breath in my body ...
or a bullet in my gun .
You know , Mr English , I 'm going to miss you . Really .
You 're very entertaining . I thank you .
Take them away .
Good morning , everybody ,
and welcome to the breakfast show .
As the crowds are gathering here for the crowning of our first French king ...
since the year 1066 ,
call here at London FM with the top ten things you most love about the French .
We haven 't had any calls yet , uh , at all ,
but the lines are still open and I 'll give you that number again ...
0 - 2-0-7 ... zero , deux , zero , sept ...
This is not good , Johnny .
We 've got to think of something .
Wait a minute . I 've got an idea .
Hop ! Hop !
And hop ! And hop ! And stop !
Now , are you familiar ...
with the shaman throat warblers of the Guatemalan delta ?
What ?
It has long been their belief ...
that a whistle pitched at the precise resonant frequency of a metal lock ...
will vibrate the levers in such a way that the door will simply swing open .
Unbelievable .
- And kneel .
Right . Here goes .
- I can 't hear anything . - I 'm into ultrasonic .
Will you just stop all this and face facts ?
We 've failed . The only thing that can save us now is a miracle .
It worked !
- Ohh ! - Sir ?
I don 't know why you hauled yourself up that dreadful poo tube , Bough ,
when there was a perfectly good ladder right beside it .
Now , Sauvage may have fooled the country ...
with his fake archbishop and his secret agenda ,
but he hasn 't fooled me .
- So , here 's the plan .
# # Let all good people rejoice # #
# # Rejoice # #
- # # Rejoice # # - Aaah !
# # Let all good people rejoice # #
# # Rejoice # #
# # And sing # #
Sirs , you are hereby called to witness the anointing ...
of your one true lord and future king Pascal .
Pascal , are you willing to take the oath ?
I am willing .
Then be thou anointed ...
with this holy oil .
And do you , the chosen bishops of England , Scotland and Wales ,
ascent to this anointing ?
For Scotland , I do .
For Wales , I do .
For England , I do not !
- - English !
That man must not be crowned king because he is ...
a fraudster , a charlatan and a thief .
No , please . Let him speak .
It is this man , Pascal Sauvage ,
who stole the Crown Jewels ,
who forced the queen to abdicate ...
and who would kill anyone who got in his way .
It is the end , Herr English .
He has cheated , conned and manipulated ...
this great country for his own ends .
He 's fooled you all !
What 's more , this whole ceremony is a sham ...
because that man standing in front of you ...
is not the archbishop of Canterbury .
English , a word of advice : Don 't go there .
Shut it , Frenchy . I 'll go wherever I damn well please .
- Now take it off . - What ?
Your face is made of plastic .
Remove it at once .
I have no idea what you 're talking about .
Right . I 'll just have to remove it myself .
Come On !
- Maybe it pulls up from the front . -
Come on , you !
- Aaah ! - Thank you very much .
Must be a join here somewhere .
Fascinating performance as always , Monsieur English ,
but I 'm afraid we must move on .
Nobody 's moving anywhere until I 'm finished with this piece of low-life .
Do you or do you you not ...
have tattooed on your bottom the words ,
" Jesus is coming ... look busy " ?
- - Are you insane ?
Well , let 's find out , shall we ?
Go on , over . Let 's have a look .
- Excellent !
All right , so I was wrong about the archbishop 's bottom .
- But there 's more . - But not , I 'm afraid , today .
Sergeant , please take this man away .
- But be gentle with him . - Do you think that 's it ?
You think I don 't have more evidence ?
My loyal subordinate is standing by with a DVD ...
which shows Sauvage 's hideous plans for this country .
Get him out ! Get him out of here !
- Play it , Bough ! Play the disk ! - Play it ! Now !
- # # You 're so hot teasing me # #
# # So you 're blue , but I can 't take a chance on a chick like you # #
# # It 's somethin I couldn 't do # #
# # Well , I can dance with you , honey if you think it 's funny # #
# # Does your mother know that you 're out # #
# # And I could shout with you , baby Flirt a little , maybe # #
- # # Take it easy # # - # # Take it easy # #
# # Better slow down , girl That 's no way to go # #
# # Does your mother know # #
- Oi ! - Hey !
Well , shall we ?
Then as Solomon was anointed king ...
by Zadok the priest and Nathan the prophet ,
so be thou anointed ...
and consecrated king ...
over all the peoples ...
whom the Lord thy God ...
hath given thee to govern ...
and of all your possessions ,
wherever they may be .
And so , in the name of the Father ...
and of the Son ...
and of the Holy Ghost ,
I crown you ...
Damn it !
- Give it back ! - NO !
- That is my crown ! - Never !
- Give it back ! - Never in a million years , Sauvage !
- Give it to me ! - Get off .
Merde !
Give it back !
- Stop ! - Shut up !
All this stupid little country have to do is stand in line ...
and do what it 's told for one miserable day !
But can it do that ?
My fragrant French ass , it can !
Merde !
- Aah !
Give it ! The crown , eh ? The crown ! Go !
And so , in the name of the Father ...
and of the Son and of the Holy Ghost ,
I crown you ...
king .
What ...
Arrest that man ...
and lock him away .
# God save the king Long live the king #
# # God save the king # #
# # Amen , amen , amen , amen Amen , amen # #
# # Ahh , amen , amen Amen , hallelujah # #
# # Amen # #
# # God save the king # #
Words can hardly express just how much we appreciate everything you 've done .
Nothing more than my duty , ma 'am .
And in return , is there anything that your queen and country can do for you ?
Well ,
since one is asking , ma 'am ...
In celebration of her return to the throne ,
the queen has declared August 5 a national holiday ...
and has conferred a knighthood on the unnamed Ml7 agent ...
responsible for foiling the plot of French businessman Pascal Sauvage .
Mr Sauvage is now awaiting trial for high treason ,
a crime which still carries the death penalty .
If found guilty , he 's asked that his brain be donated to medical science ...
to further research into the causes of hyper manic schizophrenia .
Meanwhile , the unnamed English agent has left the country ...
and has already embarked on his next challenging mission .
SOMEWHERE IN THE SOUTH OF FRANCE
Sir Johnny English .
Her Majesty did seem very grateful .
She 's not the only one .
Mmm . You are full of surprises .
Aaaah !
- Johnny ! - Oh , f ...
# # One eye on the shadows # #
# # Protecting his fellows # #
# # From sunup to the moon on his back # #
# # Sendin ' villains to Hades A hit with the ladies # #
# # A stallion in the sack # #
# # You can 't get your life back when right follows left , jack # #
# # The more you see the less you know # #
# # When others would leak it his service is secret # #
# # Plays God when it 's your time to go # #
# # Hey , fellas Don 't be jealous # #
# # When they made him they broke the mould # #
# # So charismatic with an automatic # #
# # Never prematurely shooting his load , ha # #
# # Queen and country safe and sound # #
# # With villains six feet underground # #
# # And no one knows ' cause no one 's found any trace # #
# # Of a man for all seasons # #
# # Loves ' em and leaves ' em alone # #
# # So alone # #
# # And you and I wouldn 't have a clue # #
# # Who 's doin ' what , why when and who # #
# # Up a creek with no canoe # #
# # Watch out for the man for all seasons # #
# # Loves ' em and leaves ' em alone # #
# # So alone But safe at home # #
# # But safe at home But safe at home # #
# # Queen and country safe and sound # #
# # With villains six feet underground # #
# # And no one knows ' cause no one 's found any trace # #
# # Of a man for all seasons # #
# # Loves ' em and leaves ' em alone # #
# # So alone # #
# # And you and I wouldn 't have a clue # #
# # Who 's doin ' what , why when and who # #
# # Up a creek with no canoe # #
# # Watch out for the man for all seasons # #
# # Loves ' em and leaves ' em alone # #
# # So alone But safe at home # #
# # Queen and country Safe and sound # #
# # With villains six feet underground # #
# # And no one knows ' cause no one 's found any trace # #
# # Of a man for all seasons # #
# # Loves ' em and leaves ' em alone # #
# # So alone # #
# # And you and I wouldn 't have a clue # #
# # Who 's doin ' what , why when and who # #
# # Up a creek with no canoe # #
# # Watch out for the man for all seasons # #
# # Loves ' em and leaves ' em alone # #
# # So alone # #
# # But safe at home # #
# # Oh-Oh-Ohh , yeah # #